Phrases in various languages

English  You only live once, but if you do it right, once is enough.

French  Il n’y a pas de fumée sans feu.

German  Es gibt nichts Gutes, außer man tut es.

Russian  Красота спасёт мир

Mandarin  千里之行，始于足下

Cantonese  雞同鴨講

Kanji  七転び八起き

Katakana  おれは海賊王になる！

Greek  ἓν οἶδα ὅτι οὐδὲν οἶδα

Farsi  زندگی کوتاه است، آن را زیبا بساز 

Hebrew  שְׁמַע יִשְׂרָאֵל

Hindi  जब जागो तब सवेरा।

Korean  나무를 심는데 가장 좋았던 때는 20년 전이었다. 두 번째로 좋은 때는 지금이다.

Hieroglyphics 𓋹𓍑𓋴

Vietnamese  Có chí thì nên

Thai  กันไว้ดีกว่าแก้

Arabic  من جد وجد

Inuktitut  行き ᕾᙵ ᑐᕾᙵ

Ethiopic Ge'ez  መናገር ብር ነው፤ ዝምታ ወርቅ ነው። 

Cherokee  ᎠᏯ ᎨᏍᏓ ᎯᎨᏍᏓ ᏱᏓᏟ